Guide to the Student Materials Relating to University High School, ca. 1923-1987
University Archives.
Student materials relating to University High School,
ca. 1923-1987
CU-407
5 boxes, 17 vols., (7 linear ft.)
The Bancroft Library. University Archives. Berkeley, California 94720-6000
Includes student body council minutes, student publications, student scrapbooks, memorabilia, and reunion materials.
Information for Researchers
Access
Collection is open for research.
Brief History
University High School was a six year secondary school located in Oakland from 1914 to 1946. The school was comprised of a Junior High of seventh, eighth and ninth grades, and a Senior High of tenth, eleventh and twelfth grades. The Board of Education of the City of Oakland and the Education Department of the University of California maintained and operated the school, which functioned as a state training school for secondary teachers. University High was located at 48th and Webster Streets in Oakland from 1914 to 1922; in 1922 a new school was built at 5714 Grove Street. Classes were conducted there until 1946, when, due to declining enrollment, the school was closed.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of minute books and scrapbooks of school organizations, school publications, and memorabilia (plaques, a trophy, photographs and a school banner). Included are scrapbooks concerning 1950, 1955, 1960 and 1986 class reunions, and local newspaper clippings about University High written between 1984-1986, as well as lists of alumni compiled in 1986 and 1987.
The school yearbook, The Cub and the Daily Uni, University High's daily newspaper, are housed separately in University Archives.
Container List
- Minute Books and School-Initiated Publications
  - Minutes of the Student Body Council Meetings, 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of the Student Body Council Meetings, 1926-1928 (Folder 2)
  - Minutes of the Student Body Council Meetings, 1929-1931 (Folder 3)
  - Minutes of the Student Body Council Meetings, 1931-1934 (Folder 4)
  - Autograph Book, 1931-1940 (Folder 5)
    Signatures of speakers at University High, 1931-1940
  - U.H.S. Record, 1925 (Folder 6)
  - U.H.S. Directory, Spring Semester, 1930 (Folder 7)
  - U.H.S. Directory, Janurary, 1932 (Folder 8)
- Publications of University High School, Newspaper clippings, Alumni lists
  - Cub Tracks, Oct. 1925; January, April, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    A literary magazine.
  - Cub Tracks, June, October, 1926; January, April, 1927 (Folder 2)
  - Cub Tracks, June, October, December, 1927 (Folder 3)
  - Cub Tracks, March, October, December, 1928 (Folder 4)
  - The Lookout, February, 1928
    A literary magazine of the Junior High.
  - The Spade (Yearbook) June, 1938; June, 1940 (Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 6)
    - Program: "The Dramatic Workshop at University High School Presents Four One-Act Plays, Friday Evening, May 4, 1926."
    - Program: "The Builder," June 9, 1933. Commencement Ceremony of the Class of June 1933.
    - Schedule of classes, Spring, 1940
  - Newspaper clippings, 1984-1986 (Folder 7)
  - Listings (Names, addresses, telephone numbers) of University High School Alumni. (Folder 8)
    List 1 compiled 5/15/86. Supplement compiled 2/7/87
- Memorabilia
  - Loose Scrapbook pages, Girls' League Federation (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth Chappel, Class of June, 1920 Albert Ehrgott, Jr., Class of 1920, Photographs. (Folder 2)
  - "For Scholarship-Sportsmanship and Proficiency in Athletics," 1922-1926 1927-1941, 2 plaques. (Folder 3)
  - "Sportsmanship," 1943-1946, 1 plaque. (Folder 4)
  - Perpetual Trophy, "High School Tennis League, Boys, City of Oakland, California," 1920-1926 (Box 4)
- School Banner
  - Banner donated by the Class of 1932. With signatures. (Box 5)
- Scrapbooks
  - Social Affairs, 1938-1943 (Volume v. 1-6)
  - Scrapbook of the W.B. Society, 1923-1932 (Volume v. 7)
  - Autograph book of graduating class members, 1925-1946 (Volume v. 8)
  - Student Activities, 1937-1942 (Volume v. 9)
  - The Who's Who Committee, 1937-1943 (Volume v. 10)
  - Scrapbook of the Class of 1938 (Volume v. 11)
  - Girls' League Post-Mortem, Fall, 1942 (Volume v. 12)
  - University High School Finance Committee, 1940-1943 (Volume v. 13)
  - Scrapbooks of Irene Mlejnek, 1942-1944 and 1942-1946 Student at University High (Volume v. 14-15)
  - Scrapbook concerning 1950, 1955 and 1960 reunions (Volume v. 16)
  - Scrapbook concerning reunion for the years 1918-1946, held on May 3, 1986 (Volume v. 17)